TeleLearning Network Inc. fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
TeleLearning Network Inc. fonds
1994 - 2002
F-172
Q106643134
2.88 m of textual records and other material
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
PHYSICAL DESCRIPTION Fonds includes 1783.9 mb. of multiple media records (electronic), 116 audio cassettes, 135 negatives, 16 contact sheets, 73 digital photographs (.jpg, .gif, .pct formats), 26 photographic transparencies, 16 photographic prints, 5 slides, 3 plaques, 1 sculpture, and 1 scrapbook. GENERAL NOTE Photographic material is located mainly in sub-series 4-6, with some additonal photos in sub-series 4-1. Sound recordings are found in series 5, artefacts in series 5 and sub-series 4-6. Electronic records are distributed across most series.
Financial assistance for the arrangement and description of the records and production of the finding aid was generously provided by the TeleLearning Network Inc., and the Office of the Vice-President President Research (Simon Fraser University).
TeleLearning Network Inc.
The TeleLearning Network of Centres of Excellence (TL-NCE) was established in 1995 when the federal government's Networks of Centres of Excellence (NCE) program awarded a grant to create a network of researchers from Canadian universities, focusing on the development and application of networked technologies in education and training. TeleLearning established a management office to administer its affairs, and on April 7 1997 the office incorporated under the Corporations Act as TeleLearning Network Inc. (TN Inc.), a not-for-profit corporation. Ostensibly two separate bodies, each with its own Board of Directors, in practice TL-NCE and TN Inc. were not distinct: Board members were identical for both and the same Board session dealt with the affairs of both. TL-NCE was the "research face" and TN Inc. the "legal-administrative face" of the same organization. TeleLearning's renewal application in 2001 for a second round of NCE funding was unsuccessful. The decision was made to close out the Network, and on September 30, 2002 the corporation was officially dissolved.
TeleLearning's mandate was to research, develop and demonstrate effective knowledge-building pedagogies, implemented through telelearning; to support the development of a knowledge economy and learning society in Canada; and to transfer the resulting knowledge into Canadian organizations, institutions of learning and Canadian companies for worldwide exploitation. Its main functions were to organize further research and distribute funding to individual projects through seven distinct research themes; publicize research results through publications, reports, and conferences; promote cooperation among private, public and university sectors; and encourage the development of commercial applications and technologies through the formation of spin-off companies.
TeleLearning was primarily funded by the federal government through the NCE programs of the Natural Science and Engineering Research Council of Canada (NSERC), the Social Sciences and Humanities Research Council of Canada (SSHRC), and Industry Canada. Additional funding was obtained through TeleLearning membership fees from participating public and private-sector organizations, including international affiliates. The chief officers of the Network were the Network Leader, Network Co-Leader, and the Executive Director. The Board of Directors was responsible for the overall management and direction of the Network, with certain powers delegated to an appointed Executive Committee. Other committees advised the Board, including the Program Committee and the Knowledge and Technology Transfer Committee. Relations between the Network and member organizations was regulated by the Network Internal Agreement.
TeleLearning's management office operated out of Simon Fraser University, which served as the Network's host institution. The main functions of the management office were disbursement of funds, NCE reporting, communications, member liaison, assistance with funding proposals, and conference organization. As host institution, SFU provided TeleLearning with office space, facilities, and some administrative services (e.g. payroll and finances).
The TeleLearning Network was originally built around four "beacon technologies": Collaboration Architecture and Design Resources for Telelearning (CadreTel), Computer Supported Intentional Learning Environment (CSILE), Teleform, and Virtual-University (Virtual-U). Over 240 public- and private-sector organizations participated in its projects, including over 130 faculty from 30 Canadian universities. The Network supported the growth of the online learning industry with the development of more than 45 software prototypes. Its spin-off companies included TELEStraining Inc., ClearMed Medical Knowledge Inc., Math Resources Inc., Nomino Inc., InVentures Incubator Inc., Cogigraph, the Portal for Online Objects in Learning (POOL), and TeleLearning Solutions Inc.
published
Full
Revised
Title of the fonds is based on the name of its creator.
The fonds consists of records made or received by the TeleLearning Network's management office in the course of administering the Network's affairs.
Activities documented include Annual General Meetings and meetings of the Board of Directors and TeleLearning committees, Network financial administration and budgeting, communications, media relations and web presence, the holding of annual TeleLearning Conferences, NCE reporting, management of research projects, and promotion of TeleLearning spin-off companies.
Records include meeting agendas, minutes and supporting papers; NCE application submissions and working papers; reports, including Annual Reports, NCE statistical reports and the final NCE report; letters patent of incorporation, Network internal agreements, memoranda of agreement, by-laws, policies and procedures; correspondence, notes, and working papers; budgets, financial statements, audit reports, tax returns, year-end documents and planning documents; conference programs, audio tapes of conference presentations, conference promotional material and artifacts; TeleLearning software products on CD ROM, and TeleLearning's web site (burned onto a CD in September 2002); communications plan, press releases and press clippings.
Record media include paper, electronic (spreadsheets, word-processing documents, graphics formats, and html files), optical disks, audio tapes, photographs, graphics and artifacts.
Arrangement is based on the filing system of the TeleLearning management office.
Guest, Peter; Curry, Joanne; Harasim, Linda; Calvert, Thomas W.; Sound recordings; Photographic materials; Artefacts; Textual records; Communications; Education; Science and technology
The Archives acquired the records directly from the TeleLearning management office in 2002.
All accessions have been processed as of February 2003. No further accruals are expected.
TeleLearning's management office located at Simon Fraser University continuously maintained custody of the records and transferred the material directly to the Archives following the dissolution of the Network in the fall of 2002.
This fonds contains only the records created by the TeleLearning management office. Associated records may be held by other institutions (e.g. partner universities) and by participating researchers themselves.
Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as stipulated by Archives policy or the donor. Files marked "pending review" must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release and, as a result of the review, access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
Access to the sound recordings in series 5 is restricted for preservation reasons due to the fragility of the storage medium (audio cassette tape). The Archives will provide access only through digitizaiton of the originals. As of October 2012 no recordings have been digitized. Consult the reference archivist for more information about access these recordings.
File and item lists are available.
- Board, committee and meeting records, 1995 - 2002; F-172-1; 54 cm of textual records 66.6 mb. of textual records (electronic)
  published
  Series consists of paper and electronic records relating to the meetings of the Board of Directors, several committees (Executive Committee, Program Commitee, Operations Committee and the Knowledge and Technology Transfer Committee), and the Annual General Meetings. Records include meeting agendas, minutes and supporting papers, correspondence, reports, planning documents, organization charts, budgets and financial statements, resolutions, attendance waiver forms, voting proxy forms, ballots, and proposals. Records are retained in both paper and electronic media.
  Series has been arranged into separate sub-series for each meeting body.
  No further accruals are expected.
  Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as stipulated by Archives policy or the donor. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
  File lists are available.
  - Board of Directors meeting records, 1995 - 2002; F-172-1-1; 25 cm of textual records 29.1 mb. of textual records (electronic)
    This sub-series consists of records relating to the meetings of the Board of Directors, in the form of the package Directors received in preparation for each meeting. Records include agendas, minutes and supporting papers; correspondence, organization charts, reports, planning documents, budgets and financial statements, communication plans, resolutions, attendance waiver forms, voting proxy forms, ballots, and proposals. The sub-series also includes the Executive Director's file of notes relating to the Board. Both paper and electronic records have been retained, and there is some duplication of documents across media. Electronic records are retained in their original software formats (primarily .doc and .ppt).
    Files are arranged chronologically by meeting date.
    Some information on Board structure and policy is also available in series F-172-2, "Administrative and operational subject files."
    A file list is available.
    - Board of Directors meeting agendas and supporting papers, vol. 1, 1995; F-172-1-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 172-1)
      Textual records
      Pending review
    - Board of Directors meeting agendas and supporting papers, vol. 1, 1996; F-172-1-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 172-1)
    - Board of Directors meeting agendas and supporting papers, 1997; F-172-1-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 172-1)
    - Board of Directors meeting agendas and supporting papers, vol. 1, 1998; F-172-1-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 172-1)
    - Board of Directors meeting agendas and supporting papers, vol. 1, 1999; F-172-1-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 172-1)
    - Board of Directors meeting agendas and supporting papers, vol. 2, 1999; F-172-1-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 172-1)
    - Board of Directors meeting agendas and supporting papers, vol. 1, 2000; F-172-1-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 172-1)
    - Board of Directors meeting agendas and supporting papers, vol. 2, 2000; F-172-1-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 172-2)
    - Board of Directors meeting agendas and supporting papers, vol. 1, 2001; F-172-1-1-0-9 (Archival box - standard 172-2)
      Restricted in whole
    - Board of Directors meeting agendas and supporting papers, vol. 1, 2002; F-172-1-1-0-10 (Archival box - standard 172-2)
    - Board of Directors meeting minutes, 1995 - 2001; F-172-1-1-0-11 (Archival box - standard 172-2)
    - Transition Board of Directors meeting agendas, minutes and supporting papers, vol. 1, 2002; F-172-1-1-0-12 (Archival box - standard 172-2)
    - Board of Directors notes - Executive Director, 1996 - 2002; F-172-1-1-0-13 (Archival box - standard 172-2)
    - Board of Directors meeting agendas and supporting papers, vol. 2, 1995; F-172-1-1-0-14
    - Board of Directors meeting agendas and supporting papers, vol. 2, 1996; F-172-1-1-0-15
    - Board of Directors meeting agendas and supporting papers, vol. 2, 1998; F-172-1-1-0-16
    - Board of Directors meeting agendas and supporting papers, vol. 3, 1999; F-172-1-1-0-17
    - Board of Directors meeting agendas and supporting papers, vol. 3, 2000; F-172-1-1-0-18
    - Board of Directors meeting agendas and supporting papers, vol. 2, 2001; F-172-1-1-0-19
    - Board of Directors meeting agendas and supporting papers, vol. 2, 2002; F-172-1-1-0-20
    - Transition Board of Directors meeting agendas, minutes and supporting papers, vol. 2, 2002; F-172-1-1-0-21
  - Executive Committee meeting records, 1996 - 2002; F-172-1-2; 12 cm of textual records 12.6 mb. of textual records (electronic)
    This subseries conists of records relating to the meetings of the Executive Committee. Records include agendas, minutes, supporting papers, correspondence, presentations and reports. Both paper and electronic records have been retained, and there is some duplication of documents across media. Electronic records are retained in their original software formats (primarily .doc and .ppt).
    - Executive Committee meeting agendas, 1998 - 2001; F-172-1-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 172-3)
    - Executive Committee meeting agenda and supporting papers, 1999; F-172-1-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 172-3)
    - Executive Committee meeting minutes, 1996 - 2002; F-172-1-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 172-3)
    - Joint Executive Committee and Program Committee meeting, 2000, F-172-1-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 172-3)
    - Executive Committee meeting agendas, minutes and supporting papers, 1998; F-172-1-2-0-5
    - Executive Committee meeting agendas, minutes and supporting papers, 1999; F-172-1-2-0-6
    - Executive Committee meeting agendas, minutes and supporting papers, 2000; F-172-1-2-0-7
    - Executive Committee meeting agendas, minutes and supporting papers, 2001; F-172-1-2-0-8
    - Executive Committee meeting agendas, minutes and supporting papers, 2002; F-172-1-2-0-9
  - Program Committee meeting records, 1995 - 2001; F-172-1-3; 13 cm of textual records 19.9 mb. of textual records (electronic)
    This sub-series consists of records relating to the meetings of the Program Committee. Records include agendas, minutes, supporting papers, correspondence, presentations and reports. Both paper and electronic records have been retained, and there is some duplication of documents across media. Electronic records are retained in their original software formats (primarily .doc and .ppt).
    - Program Committee meeting minutes, 1995 - 2001; F-172-1-3-0-1 (Archival box - standard 172-4)
    - Program Committee meeting agendas and supporting papers, 1996, F-172-1-3-0-2 (Archival box - standard 172-4)
    - Program Committee meeting agendas and supporting papers, 1997, F-172-1-3-0-3 (Archival box - standard 172-4)
    - Program Committee meeting agendas and supporting papers, 1998, F-172-1-3-0-4 (Archival box - standard 172-4)
    - Program Committee meeting agendas and supporting papers, 1999-2000, F-172-1-3-0-5 (Archival box - standard 172-4)
    - Program Committee meeting notes and correspondence - Executive Director, 1996 - 1999; F-172-1-3-0-6 (Archival box - standard 172-4)
    - Program Committee meeting, agendas, minutes and supporting papers, 1998; F-172-1-3-0-7
    - Program Committee meeting, agendas, minutes and supporting papers, 1999; F-172-1-3-0-8
    - Program Committee meeting, agendas, minutes and supporting papers, 2000; F-172-1-3-0-9
    - Program Committee meeting, agendas, minutes and supporting papers, 2001; F-172-1-3-0-10
  - Annual General Meeting records, 1996 - 2002; F-172-1-4; 4 cm of textual records 3.4 mb. of textual records (electronic)
    This sub-series consists of records relating to the sessions of the AGM. Records include agendas, minutes and supporting papers, correspondence, reports, resolutions, and proxy and waiver forms. Both paper and electronic records have been retained, and there is some duplication of documents across media. Electronic records are retained in their original software formats (.doc).
    - Annual General Meetings agendas, 1998 - 2001; F-172-1-4-0-1 (Archival box - standard 172-5)
    - Annual General Meetings - general file, 2001 - 2002; F-172-1-4-0-2 (Archival box - standard 172-5)
    - Annual General Meeting '96-'97, 1996 - 1997; F-172-1-4-0-3
    - Annual General Meeting '98, 1998; F-172-1-4-0-4
    - Annual General Meeting '99, 1999; F-172-1-4-0-5
    - Annual General Meeting '00, 2000; F-172-1-4-0-6
    - Annual General Meeting '01, 2001; F-172-1-4-0-7
  - Operations Committee meeting records, 1998 - 2000; F-172-1-5; 0.65 mb. of textual records (electronic)
    This sub-series consists of records relating to the meetings of the Operations Committee. Records include meeting agendas, minutes and supporting papers. Records are retained only in an electronic medium, in their original software format (.doc).
    For other information and records relating to this committee, see also the sub-series F-173-4-1, "Communications Manager's subject files," file 21 "Operations Committee."
    - Operations Committee meeting agendas, minutes and supporting papers, 1998 - 2000; F-172-1-5-0-1
  - Knowledge and Technology Transfer Committee meeting records, 1997 - 2000; F-172-1-6; 1.5 mb. of textual records (electronic)
    This sub-series consists of records relating to the meetings of the Knowledge and Technology Transfer Committee. Records include meeting agendas, minutes and supporting papers. Records are retained only in an electronic medium, in their original software format (.doc and .xls).
    For other material relating to technology transfer, see also series F-172-7, "Spin-off companies." Reports of the Committee may be found in sub-series F-172-1-1, "Board of Directors meeting records."
    - Knowledge and Technology Transfer Committee meeting agendas, minutes and supporting papers, 1997 - 2000; F-172-1-6-0-1
- Administrative and operational subject files, 1994 - 2002; F-172-2; 76 cm of textual records 51.3 mb. of textual records (electronic)
  This series consists of records relating to the general administration of the Network through the management office. Activities documented include establishment of the Network, development of policy and governance structures, strategic planning, incorporation, liaison with member institutions, liaison with the federal Networks of Centres of Excellence (NCE) program and other NCEs, TeleLearning's mid-term review in 1998 and its renewal application in 2000.
  Records includes correspondence, reports (including Annual Reports and the final NCE report), statistics, polices and procedures, insurance policies, agreements (including the Network Internal Agreement), Network by-laws, letters patent of incorporation, funding applications and planning documents. Both paper and electronic records have been retained, and there is some duplication of documents across media. Electronic records are retained in their original software formats (.doc .xls, .ppt, .pdf, .jpg).
  Files are arranged alphabetically.
  - Annual reports, 1996 - 2001; F-172-2-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 172-6)
  - Awards notification, 1996 - 2002; F-172-2-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 172-6)
  - Board of Directors liability insurance policy, 2001 - 2002; F-172-2-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 172-6)
  - Board structure - Executive Director's file, 1996; F-172-2-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 172-6)
  - By-laws, 2002; F-172-2-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 172-6)
  - Canadian Genetic Diseases Network (CDGN), 1997; F-172-2-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 172-6)
    Canadian Genetic Diseases Network; Textual records
  - Expert Panel site visit, 1998; F-172-2-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 172-6)
  - Extension funding - request, 2001 - 2002; F-172-2-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 172-6)
  - Extension funding - distribution, 2002; F-172-2-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 172-7)
  - Final NCE report, 2001 - 2002; F-172-2-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 172-7)
    Open
  - Funding agreement, 1999 - 2002; F-172-2-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 172-7)
  - GST requirements, 1996 - 2001; F-172-2-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 172-7)
  - Health Evidence Application and Linkage Network (HEALNet), 1996 - 1998; F-172-2-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 172-7)
    Health Evidence Application and Linkage Network; Textual records
  - Incorporation guidelines, 1997 - 2002; F-172-2-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 172-7)
  - Intelligence Sensing for Innovative Structuring (ISIS), 1996 - 1998; F-172-2-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 172-7)
  - Memorandum of Agreement, 1997; F-172-2-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 172-7)
  - Memberships - general information and correspondence, 1996 - 2001; F-172-2-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 172-7)
  - Midterm review, vol. 1, 1998; F-172-2-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 172-8)
  - Midterm review, vol. 2, 1998; F-172-2-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 172-8)
  - Midterm review, vol. 3, 1998; F-172-2-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 172-8)
  - NCE annual statistical report 1996-1997, F-172-2-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 172-8)
  - NCE annual statistical report 1997-1998, F-172-2-0-0-22 (Archival box - standard 172-8)
  - NCE annual statistical report 1998-1999, F-172-2-0-0-23 (Archival box - standard 172-8)
  - NCE annual statistical report 1999-2000, F-172-2-0-0-24 (Archival box - standard 172-8)
  - NCE annual statistical report 2000-2001, F-172-2-0-0-25 (Archival box - standard 172-8)
  - NCE annual statistical report 2001-2002, 2000 - 2001; F-172-2-0-0-26 (Archival box - standard 172-8)
  - NCE renewal application, vol. 1, 1996 - 2000; F-172-2-0-0-27 (Archival box - standard 172-8)
  - NCE renewal application, vol. 2, 1996 - 2000; F-172-2-0-0-28 (Archival box - standard 172-8)
  - NCE renewal application - submission: Renewal Application, 2000; F-172-2-0-0-29 (Archival box - standard 172-9)
  - NCE renewal application - submission: Progress Report, 2000; F-172-2-0-0-30 (Archival box - standard 172-9)
  - NCE renewal application - submission: Letters of Support, 2000; F-172-2-0-0-31 (Archival box - standard 172-9)
  - NCE renewal application - submission: Curriculum Vitae for Network Investigators, 2000; F-172-2-0-0-32 (Archival box - standard 172-9)
  - NCE renewal application - financial portion, vol. 1, 2000; F-172-2-0-0-33 (Archival box - standard 172-9)
  - NCE renewal application - financial portion, vol. 2, 2000; F-172-2-0-0-34 (Archival box - standard 172-9)
  - NCE renewal application - financial portion, vol. 3, 2000; F-172-2-0-0-35 (Archival box - standard 172-9)
  - NCE renewal application - decision, 2000 - 2001; F-172-2-0-0-36 (Archival box - standard 172-9)
  - Network Internal Agreement, 1995 - 1996; F-172-2-0-0-37 (Archival box - standard 172-10)
  - Network Internal Agreement - Executive Director's file, vol. 1, 1995 - 1996; F-172-2-0-0-38 (Archival box - standard 172-10)
  - Network Internal Agreement - Executive Director's file, vol. 2, 1995 - 1996; F-172-2-0-0-39 (Archival box - standard 172-10)
  - Office insurance policy, 1997 - 2002; F-172-2-0-0-40 (Archival box - standard 172-10)
  - Original Letter of Intent, proposal and strategic plan, 1994; F-172-2-0-0-41 (Archival box - standard 172-10)
  - Phase II, Year II general documents, 2000; F-172-2-0-0-42 (Archival box - standard 172-10)